Finding Aid for the Verley Archer Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Verley Archer Collection
1960’s-1980’s
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0254
8.76 linear feet
Scope and Content Note
The Verley Archer Collection consists of materials relating to the Vanderbilt Family Reunion held in conjunction with the Centennial Celebration of Vanderbilt University, March 16-17, 1973. Ms. Archer conducted extensive research into the genealogy of the Vanderbilt family and located descendants of Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt living in 1973.
Included in the Verley Archer Collection are research notes and materials, completed questionnaires from family members, correspondence, publicity materials, and published books, all relating to the Family Reunion and Centennial Celebration.
The 21 boxes in this collection cover approximately 8.76 linear feet. The collection is arranged in 3 series: Subject Files (Series 1); Vanderbilt Centennial (series 2); and Verley Archer’s Research Materials (Series 3).
The Subject Files, Series 1, are the most extensive part of this collection. They consist of letters, completed questionnaires, and biographical information on most of the over 500 members of the Vanderbilt family living in 1973, as well as some earlier family members. These are arranged alphabetically by last name. Married women descendants are cross-referenced by their maiden names.
Series 2 consists of the form letter mailings sent to his Vanderbilt relatives by William H. Vanderbilt, III and their responses. Also included are publicity articles about the Vanderbilt Family Reunion and Vanderbilt University Centennial. There are lists of descendants attending the Reunion and of gifts to Vanderbilt University from the descendants. Materials related to the project administration are included as well as the printed programs commemorating the Centennial festivities. There are draft copies of the genealogical charts and the genealogical book compiled by Ms Archer. There is also a copy of her book, Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt, Sophia Johnson Vanderbilt, and Their Descendants, published by Vanderbilt University in 1973 and materials relating to its publication.
Ms. Archer’s research comprises Series 3. It includes photocopies of articles about the Vanderbilt family, ranging from their arrival in America in 1650 up through their activities in the early 1970’s. There are also books and newspaper articles about contemporary Vanderbilts, especially concerning their publications or publications in which they are mentioned, foundations with which they are associated, and the William K. Vanderbilt Museum in Centerport, Long, Island, New York.
This collection is of special interest to those researching the Vanderbilt family and its connection with Vanderbilt University. Additionally, to quote Ms. Archer, “This has really been a study in sociology because this is such a vital, vigorous family with wide-ranging interests”
Biographical Sketch
Verley Archer was born in Springfield, Tennessee, in 1917. After graduating from high school in Hopkinsville, Kentucky, in 1937, she took a typing course and worked at a variety of jobs. At the beginning of World War II, she was recruited for clerical work at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base in Ohio, but because of her intelligence and organizational skills, she was taught Chinese in six weeks by Colonel Wang, a Chinese officer assigned to Wright-Patterson, and thereafter she taught technical English to Chinese Air Force trainees sent to the United States.
After the war, Ms. Archer took a journalism course at the University of Dayton and for the next several years she worked as a fund-raiser and writer for trade journals in San Francisco, Portland, Seattle, Philadelphia, and New York. In 1958, she returned to Tennessee and was hired by Vanderbilt University, first working in the Economic Development Office, and two years later, transferring to the Office of Alumni and Development.
Because of her fund-raising activities for this office, Ms. Archer became interested in the Vanderbilt family. By 1968, with the support of Chancellor Alexander Heard, she had embarked upon her genealogical researches which culminated in the publication in 1973 by Vanderbilt University of her Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt, Sophia Johnson Vanderbilt, and Their Descendants. While she was involved in the writing of this book and in preparations for the Vanderbilt Centennial, Ms. Archer was also enrolled at Peabody College, graduating in 1974 with a B.S. degree.
She continued to work in the Alumni and Development Office at Vanderbilt until failing health forced her to retire in 1979. Even then, she continued to work from home for Vanderbilt University as a consultant on genealogy of the Vanderbilt family. Ms. Archer died December 20, 1982.
- Box Listing
  - Series I: Subject Files
    - Adams, Mrs. John Payson (Muriel Vanderbilt) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Mrs. Lorna (Lorna McClenahan) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Auchincloss, Andrew (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Auchincloss, Blake (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Auchincloss, John (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Auchincloss, Mrs. Louis (Adele Lawrence) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Avedon, Mrs. Keith (Elizabeth Ewarts Cox) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Baker, Mrs. Francis E. (Patricia Barry) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Balding, Dawn Bakom (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Balding, Robert Matthews (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Baldwin, Anne Colby Newburg (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin, Barbara Louise (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Baldwin, Robert Scott (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Balsan, Mrs. Jacque (Consuelo Vanderbilt, formerly Duchess of Marlborough) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bard, Mrs. John C. (Marjorie Jackson) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barry, Lucy B. (see Robe, Mrs. Robert S., Box 10, File 3) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Barry, Herbert, III (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Barry, Mrs. Manning (Lucy Brown) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Barry, Patricia (see Baker, Mrs. Francis E., Box 1, File 8) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Berle, Adolph Augustus (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Berle, Beatrice Lila (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Berle, Mary Alice (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berle, Mrs. Peter A.A. (Lila Sloane Wilde) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Berle, Robert Thomas (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bilotti, Mrs. Anton (Muriel Bilotti) (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Birch, Mrs. Timothy Campbell (Alexandra Brenda Russell) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bitting, Mrs. Jonathan K. (Elizabeth S. Safe) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Borgfeldt, Mrs. Merton (Marian Morris) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Bosanquet, Mrs. Charles (Barbara Schieffelin) (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bosanquet, Charles Jay (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bosanquet, Deborah L. (see Mott-Trille, Mrs. Frank, Box 9, File 7) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bosanquet, Katherine (see Rossen, Mrs. Roger, Box 10, File 7) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bostwick, Mrs. Dunbar W. (Electra Webb) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bostwick, Dundeen (see Catlin, Mrs. Daniel, Jr., Box 2, File 35) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bostwick, Electra (see McDowell, Mrs. Fletcher H., Box 8, File 23) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bostwick, Elliot (see Wood, Mrs. L. Phillips, Box 13, File 22) (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Bradley, Mrs. Cameron (Anne Louise Schieffelin) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bradley, Edith (see Perkins, Mrs. Francis, Jr., Box 9, File 37) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bradley, Helen (see Curtis, Mrs. John, Box 4, File 1) (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Bradley, Nathaniel C. (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Brady, Kenneth Parsons (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Brady, Philip V. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Breck, Mrs. Manley du Pont (Rachel Hammond) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Brown, Alice O. (see Spenser, Mrs. Richard, Box 10, File 40) (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Brown, Archibald Manning, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Brown, Mr. and Mrs. Archibald Manning, III (both are descendants- Laura Havemeyer Webb) (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Brown, Mrs. Charles Steele (Mary Jay Schieffelin) (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Brown, Charles Steele, Jr. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Brown, Christopher (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Brown, Helen M. (see Dodge, Mrs. Washington, Box 4, File 21) (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Brown, Hillary (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Brown, Hope (see Canfield, Mrs. Franklin, Box 2, File 26) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Brown, Hope (see Perlberg, Mrs. Edward B., Box 9, File 38) (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Brown, James P. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Brown, Mary L. (see Cox, Mrs. Maxwell, Box 3, File 32) (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Brown, Mrs. Newell (Alice Dodge Osborn) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Brown, Robert Peabody (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Brown, Robinson Osborn (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Brown, Rosalind (see McClellan, Mrs. John, Box 8, File 17) (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Brown, Shepard (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Browne, Francis Sedgwick (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Browne, George Morgan, IV (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Browne, Marion L. (see Dickerman, Mrs. William C., Box 4, File 18) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Browne, Nicholas Cabot (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Bruguire, Mrs. Louis (Margaret L. Post) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bulkelley-Johnson, Mrs. John Cecil (Cornelia Stuyvesant Vanderbilt) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Burden, Andrew White (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Burden, Christopher (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Burden, Elise White (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Burden, Flobelle (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Burden, Florence (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Burden Hamilton Twombly (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Burden, James A., III (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Burden, Margaret (see Childs, Mrs. Daniel, Box 3, File 7) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Burden, Ordway Partridge (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Burden, Robert Livingston (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Burden, Sheila (see Lawrence, Mrs. Blake, Box 7, File 22) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Burden, (Mr.) Shirley Carter, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Burden, Shirley Carter, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Burden, Shirley Carter, III (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Burden, Wendy (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Burden, Mrs. William A.M. (Florence Vanderbilt Twombly) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Burden, William A.M., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Burden, William A.M., III (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Burden, William A.M., IV (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Burden, William Douglas (& Mrs. Elizabeth C. Gammack) (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Burden, William Douglas, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Burden, William Douglas, III (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Burnes, Mrs. Kennett F. (Barbara Jackson) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Canfield, Mrs. Franklin Olmstead (Hope Brown) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Canfield, Hope (see Tetrault, Mrs. Jacques, Box 11, File 10) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Carswell, Kate (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Carswell, Mrs. Robert (Mary Kileen Wilde) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Carswell, William Wilde (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Carter, Alice S. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Carter, Mr. and Mrs. Fred D. Jr. (Susan Bliss Morris) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Carter, Fred D.,Jr. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Catlin, Blake Havemeyer (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Catlin, Dan Waldron (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Catlin, Mrs. Daniel, Jr. (Dundeen Bostwick) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Catlin, Todd Bostwick (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cecil, Christopher H.A. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cecil, George Harry Vanderbilt (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cecil, William Amherst Vanderbilt (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cecil, William Amherst Vanderbilt, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Childs, Constance C. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Childs, Mrs. Daniel (Margaret Burden) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Childs, Florence T. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Childs, Frederick C. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Childs, Nicholas F. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Christ, Mrs. Donald (Iris A. Smith) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Churchill, Lady Caroline Spenser- (see Waterhouse, Mrs. Charles, Box 12, File 18) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Churchill, Charles George William Collin Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Churchill, Charles James Spenser- (The Marquess of Blandford) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Churchill, Lady Henrietta Mary Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Churchill. Lady Ivor Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Churchill, John Albert Edward William Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Churchill, John George Vanderbilt Henry Spenser- (The 11th Duke of Marlborough) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Churchill, Robert William Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Churchill, Rosemary Spenser- (see Muir, Mrs. Robert, Box 9, File 8) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Churchill, Rupert John Harold Mark Spenser- (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Churchill, Sarah C. Spenser- (see Roubanis, Mrs. Theodor, Box 10, File 8) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Clark, Edith (see Milliken, Mrs. Minot, Box 8, File 36) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Clark, James Cameron, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Conner, Mrs. McCauley (Gertrude Whitney Henry) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Cook, Averill H. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Cook, John R., Jr. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Cook, Rebecca (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Cook, Warren (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cook, Willard P. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Cooper, Anderson (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Cooper, Carter (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Cooper, Mrs. Wyatt (Gloria Laura Morgan Vanderbilt) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Costin, Mrs. Brackenridge (Serena Vanderbilt Van Ingen) (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Coudenhove-Kalergi, Countess Hans Heinrich (Cornelia Carter Roberts) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Cox, Elizabeth (see Avedon, Mrs. Keith, Box 1, File 7) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Cox, Mrs. Maxwell (Mary L. Brown) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Cox, Rachel S. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Cox, Robert Hill (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Cunningham, Charles Seth (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Cunningham, Dudley H. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Cunningham, Mrs.Thomas D.,Jr. (Alice Louise Mills) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Cunningham, Thomas C. III (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Curtis, Mrs. John A., III (Helen Bradley) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cushing, Harry Cook, IV (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Daley, Sheila Bradley (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Darling, Holly Ann Havemeyer (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Darling, Mrs. Michael (Holly Webb) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Darling, Michael, Jr. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Darling, Peter (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Darling, Sean (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - David, Mrs. George A.L. (Barbara D. Osborn) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Davis, Alexandra (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Davis, Christopher William (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Davis, Elliot (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Davis, Jonathan Bostwick (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dexter, Christopher (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Dexter, Mrs. Jack (Shirley Duckworth) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Deeter, Jenifer (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Deeter, Merritt (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dickerman, Mrs. William C. (Marion LaBau Browne) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Dodge, Arthur P. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Dodge, Cornelia Therese (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Dodge, Mrs. Washington (Helen Manning Brown) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Dooley, Mrs. John (Hope Williams Schieffelin) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Duckworth, Gillian A. (see Hunt, Mrs. Duncan, Box 6, File 7) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Duckworth, Shirley (see Dexter, Mrs. Jack, Box 4, File 15) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Duckworth, Sophia (see Schrachter, Mrs. Stanley, Box 10, File 13) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Dunn, Cassandra (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Dunn, Linda (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Dunn, Michael (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Dunn, Mrs. William T., Jr. (Laura M. Franklin) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Earl, Mrs. N. Clarkson (Consuelo Vanderbilt) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Earle, Frederick O. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Earle, Mrs. Morris (Virginia Osborn) (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Earle, Morris, III (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Earle, Ralph Harding (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Earle, Walter K., II (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Ellsworth, Mrs. DeWelle (Margaret Laura Erickson) (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Eltz, Mrs. Alexander (Nadine Szechenyi) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Eltz, Nicholas (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Eltz, Peter (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Emery, Mrs. John (Adele Hammond) (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Erickson, Aileen Osborn (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Erickson, Cecile Mary (see Mactaggart, Mrs. Sandy, Box 8, File 4) (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Erickson, Josiah Macy, Jr. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Erickson, Margaret L. (see Ellsworth, Mrs. DeWelle, Box 4, File 33) (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Erickson, Silvanus Osborn (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Fabbri, Mrs. Ernesto (Edith Shepard) (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Fabbri Teresa (see McMurty, Mrs. George, Box 8, File 26) (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Fairchild, Mrs. John Douglas (Emily S. Franklin) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Field, Diana Sloane (see Koite, Mrs. John, Box 7, File 20) (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Field, Frederick Vanderbilt (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Field, John Osgood (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Field, Lila (see Jacob, Mrs. Harry, Box 6, File 22) (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Field, Marjorie L. (see Wilde, Mrs. H. George, Box 13, File 13) (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Field, Mary Augusta (see Jackson, Mrs. Henry, Box 6, File 20) (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Field, Mrs. Michael (Alice L. Wilde) (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Field, William Bradhurst Osgood, Jr. (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Franklin, Emily S. (see Fairchild, Mrs. John D., Box 4, File 42) (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Franklin, Laura M. (see Dunn, Mrs. William F., Box 4, File 26) (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Gabaldoni, Barbara (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Galbadoni, Luis (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Galbadoni, Mrs. Stephen (Dundeen Webb) (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Gamble, Mrs. David Samuel (Frederika Vanderbilt Webb) (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Gamble, David Samuel, Jr (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Gamble, Frederika G. (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Goodman, Mrs. Benny (Alice Hammond) (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Goodman, Benjie (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Goodman, Rachel (see Weisman, Mrs. Robert, Box 13, File 1) (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Hadik, Countess Bela (Alice Szchenyi) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Hadik, John Bela (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Hadik, Laszlo (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hadley, Mrs. Hamilton (Emily Hammond Morris) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Hahn, Mrs. Henry (Nancy M. Wilde) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Helen (see Holmes, Mrs. Samuel, Box 5, File 53) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hale, Herbert Dudley, Jr. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hammond, Adele (see Emery, Mrs. John, Box 4, File 37) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hammond, Alice (see Goodman, Mrs. Benny, Box 4, File 53) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hamond, Jason (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Hammond, Mrs. John Henry (Emily Vanderbilt Sloane) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Hammond, John (& Mrs. Esme O”Brien Sarnoff Hammond) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Hammond, John Paul (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Hammond, Rachel (see Breck, Mrs. Manley du Pont, Box 1, File 34) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Hanbury, Mrs. Evan Robert (Rosalind Jeanette Pease) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Hannon, Frances Gleason Browne (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Hardie, Mrs. James A. (Elizabeth Lee Mills) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Mrs. George I.E. (Kate B. Webb) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Mrs. Jones (Heidi Murray Vanderbilt) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Harshman, Cecily Cooper (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Harshman, Edward Jay (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Harshman, Mrs. Richard (Mary Ashley Cooper Hewitt) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Harshman, Thomas Ringwood (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hartwell, Ann Colby (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Hartwell, Charlotte M. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Hartwell, Ellen (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Hartwell, Mrs. Samuel A., Jr. (Anne C. Vanderbilt) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Hartwell, Samuel A., III (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Hatton, Sir Christopher Denys Stormont Finch- (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Hatton, Cynthia Lyon Finch- (see Murphy, Mrs. Robert, Box 9, File 9) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Hatton, Robin Heneage Finch- (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Hayne, Mrs. Gale Chamber Lain Field (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Headley, Mrs. George (Barbara Vanderbilt) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Heddens, Mrs. Kimber J. (Cornelia Vanderbilt) (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Henry, Mrs. Barbara (Barbara Webb) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Henry, Billy (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Henry, Eric (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Henry, Gertrude Whitney (see Conner, Mrs. McCauley, Box 3, File 21) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Henry, Linda (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Henry, William Barklie (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Hewitt, Andrew (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Hewitt, Edward Ringwood, II (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Hewitt, James (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Hewitt, Katherine (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Hewitt, Louise (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Hewitt, Mary Ashley Cooper (see Harshman, Mrs. Richard, Box 5, File 18) (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Hewitt, Peter (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Higinbotham, Dr. Normal L. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Holmes, Mrs. Samuel (Helen Hale) (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Hornblower, Mrs. Jonathan M. (Alexandra C. Tower) (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Houston, Mrs. Frederic Kidder (Marie Hayes Sturges) (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Houston, Thomas Rush (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Houston, Virginia Taylor (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Houston, Mrs. William (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Howat, Anne Headley (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Humes, Mrs. John Portner, Jr. (Susan Secor) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Hunt, David (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hunt, Mrs. Duncan (Gillian Alison Duckworth) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Hunt, James (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Hunt, Richard (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hurd, Victoria Marie (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Hutton, Consuelo Vanderbilt (see Seherr-Thoss, Mrs. Henry, Box 10, File 35) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hutton, Linda F. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Hutton, Muriel Vanderbilt (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Hutton, Mrs. William Langdon (and Mr. Hutton) (Virginia C. Smith) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Irving, Duncan Duer (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Irving, Fiona (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Irving, Macculloch Miller (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Irving, Mrs. Michael Henry (and Mr. Irving) (Flora Miller) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Irving, Michelle Mann (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Jackson, Barbara (see Burnes, Mrs. Kennett, Box 2, File 25) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Jackson, Frederick W. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Jackson, Mrs. Henry B. (Mary Augusta Field) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Jackson, Marjorie (see Bard, Mrs. John, Box 1, File 15) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Jackson, Thomas R. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Jacob, Mrs. Harry (Lila Field) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Judson, Consuelo Sarah Russell (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Keith, Mrs. Jonathan C. (Helen Ellis Paine) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Ketcham, Arthur Collins, Jr. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Ketcham, Arthur Collins, IV (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Ketcham, Christine Wilson (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Ketcham, David Dunham (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Ketcham, Fred Todd (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Ketcham, Helena Campbell (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Ketcham, J. Simpson Dean (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Ketcham, James Bonright (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Ketcham, Mrs. William Treadwell (Jean N. Long) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Ketcham, Mable Dunham (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Ketcham, Peter Titus (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Ketcham, Russel D. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Ketcham, Russel D., Jr. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Ketcham, Sally (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ketcham, William Kemble (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Ketcham, William Treadwell, Jr. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Kiernan, Paul Lawrence (born Gustav Kissel Kiernan) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - King, Herbert Thorn, Jr. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Kinnan, Alex P.W. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Kirkland, Mrs. David (Lila Wilmerding) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Kissel, Abbey T. (see Starr, Mrs. Louis, Box 10, File 42) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Kissel, Dorothy (see Sturges, Mrs. Edwin, Box 11, File 4) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kissel, Frank A. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kissel, Gertrude (see Marckwald, Mrs. Albert H. III, Box 8, File 5) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Kissel, Gertrude F. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Kissel, John D. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Kissel, Louise (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Kissel, Michael C. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Kissel, Peter F. F. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Kissel, Peter F. F., Jr. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Kissel, W. Thorn, Jr. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Kissel, W. Thorn, III (Box 7, Folder 18)